Gross, James Papers, Additional NLRB Research Files /4124
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
James Gross Papers, Additional NLRB Research Files
1935-1988
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Gross, James
/4124
13.5 cubic feet
13 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
7994501
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 20, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, September 30, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Professor Gross teaches Labor Law, Labor Arbitration, and a course entitled Values, Rights and Justice in Economics, Law, and Industrial Relations. He received his B.S. from LaSalle College, M.A. from Temple University, and Ph.D. from University of Wisconsin.
Professor Gross is a member of National Academy of Arbitrators and on the labor arbitration panels of the American Arbitration Association, Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service and New York State Public Employment Relations Board, as well as being a panelist named in several contracts.[www.ilr.cornell.edu/directory/jag28/biography.htm]
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4057: James Gross NLRB Files /4057 P: James Gross NLRB Photographs /4124: James Gross Papers, Additional NLRB Research Files /4166: James Gross Additional NLRB Research Files /4186: James Gross Additional Research Files /4190: James Gross Additional Research Files 5697: James A. Gross Arbitration Files 5959: James Gross Additional Arbitration Files /4079: James Gross Additional Files
Gross, James; National Labor Relations Bureau (U.S.)
7994501
- Post Taft-Hartley (Late 1940s). (Box 1)
  - Oct. 1949 Hearings Investigation of Labor - Management Relations (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Oct. 1949 Hearings Investigation of Labor-Management Relations (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Intro. Re Immediate Post- T.H. Situation Pre - T-H 1947 and Notes Related to the NLRB (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Articles Related to the NLRB, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Articles Post Tuft-Hurtley + Notes, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Articles Related to Taft Hurtley Act and USA Government, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - New York Times Articles 1948-'49, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - NYT 1948 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Harry S. Truman, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - NYT 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Harry S. Truman Library, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters in Support of the Mine Workers Strike, 1946-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - NLRB Labor Management Relations Act, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Harry S. Truman Library, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Harry S. Truman Library, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Late 1940s, Early 1950s. (Box 2)
  - Congressional Record, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - National Labor Relations Act of 1949 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Labor Relations Folder 1, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Labor Relations Folder 2, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Labor Relations Folder 3, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - NLRB, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - N.L.R.B., 1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - National Labor Relations Act of 1949 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - National Labor Relations Act of 1949 Folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Congressional Record - House, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Congressional Record - House, Senate, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 1950s NLRB materials. (Box 3)
  - NLRB + Handwritten Notes, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten Notes, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Articles from Truman Library, 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1950-1953 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report of the National Labor Relations Board 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - NLRB Annual Reports 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - NLRB Newspaper Articles, 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Harry S. Truman Library, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Harry S. Truman Library, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Harry S. Truman Library, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Congressional Record, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - N.L.R.B., 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - N.L.R.B. Newspaper Articles, 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - N.L.R.B., 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - N.L.R.B., 1949-1952 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- 1950s NLRB materials. (Box 4)
  - N.L.R.B., 1955-1960 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - N.L.R.B., 1954-1958 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Harvard Law Review "Article by Cox", 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - N.L.R.B., 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - N.L.R.B., 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - N.L.R.B., 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - N.L.R.B., 1956 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - N.L.R.B., 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - N.L.R.B., 1959 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - N.L.R.B., 1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - N.L.R.B., 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - N.L.R.B., 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- 1950s NLRB materials. (Box 5)
  - N.L.R.B., 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Law review "Article by Cox + Dunlop, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - N.L.R.B., 1955-1957 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - N.L.R.B., 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Beeson, 1954-1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - N.L.R.B., 1959-1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - N.L.R.B., 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Congressional Record 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - N.L.R.B., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Labor Management Reform Legislation Folder 1, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Labor Management Reform Legislation Folder 2, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Labor Management Reform Legislation Folder 3, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Jim Gross - Research Request, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - N.L.R.B., 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - N.L.R.B., 1954 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- 1950s NLRB materials. (Box 6)
  - Amending the National Labor Relations Act, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Interview with Judge Gerald Reilly, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Prof. Gross 'As per your Request' - Connie B., 1988 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Morris Glushein Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Gilbert V. Rosenberg Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Beatrice Stern Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Charles Halleck Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Robert Kleeb Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - James Reynolds Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Gerhard Van Arkel Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Mortimer Wolf Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Ruth Weyand Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Howard Lichtenstein Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Donn Bent Interview, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - John Fanning Interview, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - George Bott Interview, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - NLRB 50th Anniversary Conference October 23-24th, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Farmer (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - John Fanning, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - NLRB 50th Anniversary October 23-24, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - NLRB - Edward Miller, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Farmer (Box 6, Folder 22)
- 1950s NLRB materials. (Box 7)
  - Joseph Koski, Chief Clerk, Committee on Education and Labor, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Suggested Substitute for Evidence Rule in Free Speech Provision (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Unlawful Concerted Activities (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Paper on -- S.1126; H.R. 3020, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - A Bill to diminish the causes of industrial dispute (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - H.R. 3020 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - A Bill to Amend the National Labor Relations Act (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Public Interest in Strikes and How to Protect It (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - A Bill to Prescribe Fair and Equitable (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - H.R. 76; H.R. 3914; Public Law 101; S. 404; S. 360 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Hon. Andrew Jacobs (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Hon. Robert Taft (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - S.249; How Would You Revise Our Labor Laws? (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Hon. Andrew Jacobs (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - A Bill to remove certain causes of industrial disputes (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Summary of Provisions (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - H.R. 4908 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - New Orleans Industrial Union Council, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - A Bill to Amend the National Labor Relations Act, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Material of Possible Use for Post - Nov. 1938 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Comprehensive - Unfair Labor Practices of Unions (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Closed Shop (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Coercion and Mass Picketing (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Labor Legislation (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Duty to Bargain (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - NLRB Drafts and Bills (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Wood Bill (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Comments on Draft of Labor-Management Peace Act; Unfair Labor Practices, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Hadley Peoples Mfg. Co. (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous - Loose in box (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - PP2107 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Appropriation file (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - H.R. 3020; H.R. 725 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Suppl. Agreements covering Pension Plan and Insurance; H.R. 4908; H.R. 3020 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Federal Mediation Act of 1946; H.R. 3020; Public Law 101 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Subcommittee on Union Democracy, House Comm. On Education and Labor, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Union Democracy, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Portal-to-Portal Act of 1947 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Reconversion and the Fair Labor Standards Act, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Morgan papers. (Box 8)
  - Ship Sales Committee Amendments, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Confidential Committee Print Tentative Draft No. 1, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Confidential Committee Prints, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Confidential Committee Print No. 4-5, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Labor Legislation #1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Fair Labor Standouts, 1947-1948 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - National Federation of American Shipping Lewd - Lease to Great Britain, 1944-1945 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Labor, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Labor, 1947-1950 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - James C. Auchincloss, M.C., 1946 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Congressional Investigations Article for California Law Review, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Labor--Misc. (GDM), 1948 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Labor Legislation #3, 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - NLRB Arbitration Shipping Companies, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Arbitration, 1947-1949 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Morgan, 1940-1947 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Morgan papers. (Box 9)
  - Labor Bill-- Veto and Passage, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Labor Bill-- House Debates, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Labor Bill - Conference Agreement Folder 1, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Labor Bill - Conference Agreement Folder 2, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "Conference Report", 1947 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Labor Bill - Senate Debates Folder 1, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Labor Bill - Senate Debates Folder 2, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Labor Bill - Senate Debates Folder 3, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Taft-Hartley. (Box 10)
  - Preambles (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Robert Taft Papers, 1946-1949 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Taft-Hartley, 1947-1949 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Post Taft-Hartley, 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - NLRB Misc., 1950 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Personal Policy of the NLRB and Panel Members, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - The New Labor Law, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - NLRB Post Taft-Hartley, 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Post Taft-Hartley, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - NLRB, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - NLRB Post Taft-Hartley, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - NLRB Post Taft-Hartley, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - NLRB Taft-Hartley, 1947-1950 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Pre-Morgan, 1946-1949 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Pre-Morgan Folder 2, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Taft-Hartley. (Box 11)
  - NLRB Review Staff, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - NLRB, 1936-1938 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Taft-Hartley Act, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - NLRB Monograph No. 18, 1935-1939 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - NLRB, 1947-1952 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Appendix to Jurisdiction Committee Report, 1953-1954 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - NLRB Misc. Notecards, 1948-1950 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - The Labor Management Relations Act, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - NLRB Taft-Hartley Act, 1948-1952 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Motions - Board of Examiners for Hearing Examiner Personnel, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Post Taft-Hartley, 1947-1952 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - NLRB Staff Memos and Excerpts, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Majority Report, 1938-1941 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Materials Not Used Chs. 12+, 1939-1941 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - 1946, 1942-1946 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - NLRB - AFL Executive Board, 1945-1969 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - 'New Style NLRB', 1941-1945 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Legislative, 1950-1951 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Taft-Hartley. (Box 12)
  - Congressional Record - Senate, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Post Taft-Hartley, 1947-1950 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Labor Management Relations Act 1947 - Misc., 1947-1949 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Record Vol. 95, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Record Vol. 95, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Record Vol. 95, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Record Vol. 95, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Congressional Record Vol. 95, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Record Vol. 95, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Review of the Criticisms of the NLRB, 1939-1941 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Notes, and News Clippings on the Wagner Act, 1935-1976 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Berkshire Knitting Mills, 1938-1941 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Reports and Correspondence on the NLRB, 1941-1946 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Labor-Management Relations -- Joint Committee, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - The Requirement that Administrative Agencies Makes Clear the Reasons for their Decisions, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- NLRB. (Box 13)
  - Memorandum about the NLRB, 1945-1954 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - NLRB Transmittal Slips, 1947-1960 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence on the NLRB, 1938-1958 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Guy Farmer, 1953-1955 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Articles and News Clippings on the NLRB, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Report on the NLRB, 1st Congressional Session, 1941-1943 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Meeting of the NLRB Legal Staff, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Effects of Labor-Management Policy, 1939-1966 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Effects of Labor-Management Policy, 1942-1956 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Conferences and Addresses on Labor-Management Policy, 1946-1958 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Labor-Management Policies, 1941-1951 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Labor-Management Policies, 1947-1971 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Court Cases, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Library Slips, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 14)